const question = document.querySelector('#question');
const choices = Array.from(document.querySelectorAll('.choice-text'));
const progressText = document.querySelector('#progressText');
const scoreText = document.querySelector('#score');
const progressBarFull = document.querySelector('#progressBarFull');

let currentQuestion = {}
let acceptingAnswers = true
let score = 0
let questionCounter = 0
let availableQuestions = []

let questions = [

    {
        question:
        "1. OSPF discovers neighbors ______.",
        choice1: 'Only by manually configuring the router',
        choice2: 'By flooding updates',
        choice3: 'Using Hello advertisements',
        choice4: 'Using a host table',
        answer: 3,
        },							
        {
        question:
        "2. Which of the following is not a feature of the OSPF protocol?",
        choice1: 'It supports authentication.',
        choice2: 'It provides a loop-free topology.',
        choice3: 'It uses the Shortest Path First algorithm.',
        choice4: 'It uses a hop countâ€“based metric.',
        answer: 4,
        },							
        {
        question:
        "3. Which logical interface is recommended for defining a router ID?",
        choice1: 'Ethernet interface',
        choice2: 'Chassis interface',
        choice3: 'MAC address',
        choice4: 'System interface',
         answer: 4,
        },							
        {
        question:
        "4. What is the primary purpose of the OSPF router ID?",
        choice1: 'To elect a designated router',
        choice2: 'To uniquely identify an OSPF router',
        choice3: 'To trace sequence numbers',
        choice4: 'To support LSA flooding',
        answer: 2,
        },							
        {
        question:
        "5. LSA updates are sent in response to network changes and ______.",
        choice1: 'Every 30 minutes',
        choice2: 'After the Hello timer expires',
        choice3: 'When the DR detects the BDR has failed',
        choice4: 'Every 30 minutes provided new information needs to be transmitted',
        answer: 1,
        },							
        {
        question:
        "6. What does it mean to say that two OSPF routers are adjacent?",
        choice1: 'The routers are physically connected on a point-to-point link.',
        choice2: 'The routers are on a common network segment and have exchanged database information.',
        choice3: 'The routers have exchanged Hello packets.',
        choice4: 'The routers are in a single area.',
        answer: 2,
        },							
        {
        question:
        "7. What is required for OSPF routers on a point-to-point network to form an adjacency?",
        choice1: 'The DR must form an adjacency first.',
        choice2: 'The neighbor IP address must be configurecd.',
        choice3: 'They will automatically become adjacent provided certain OSPF configuration values match.',
        choice4: 'Nothing. OSPF routers on point-to-point links will always become adjacent.',
        answer: 3,
        },							
        {
        question:
        "8. Which of the following hello packet values is not involved in the adjacency process on point-to-point links?",
        choice1: 'The area ID',
        choice2: 'The priority',
        choice3: 'The Hello timer',
        choice4: 'The dead timer',
        answer: 2,
        },							
        {
        question:
        "9. In addition to having correct OSPF settings in the Hello packets, another value that can prevent routers from forming an adjacency in the event of a mismatch is ______.",
        choice1: 'The AS number',
        choice2: 'The OSPF MTU',
        choice3: 'The OSPF metric',
        choice4: 'The MPLS TE',
        answer: 2,
        },							
        {
        question:
        "10. The command to display the Link State Updates that a router has received is ______.",
        choice1: 'show router ospf status',
        choice2: 'show router ospf links',
        choice3: 'show router ospf summary',
        choice4: 'show router ospf database',
        answer: 4,
        },							
        {
        question:
        "11. There are many different types of LSAs in OSPF. The most common LSA type in point-to-point networks is ______.",
        choice1: 'The area LSA',
        choice2: 'The router LSA',
        choice3: 'The network LSA',
        choice4: 'The summary LSA',
        answer: 2,
        },							
        {
        question:
        "12. If an OSPF router receives an LSA with a sequence number that is equal to the sequence number it already has for that LSA, it will ______.",
        choice1: 'Silently drop the LSA.',
        choice2: 'Send a rejection notice to the sending router.',
        choice3: 'Drop the LSA and send an acknowledgement.',
        choice4: 'Drop the LSA and forward it to its adjacent routers.',
        answer: 3,
        },							
        {
        question:
        "13. Which of the following is false regarding the Shortest Path First algorithm that OSPF uses?",
        choice1: 'It determines the optimal route to each network.',
        choice2: 'It creates a loop-free path to each network.',
        choice3: 'It is run only on the router that originates an LSA update.',
        choice4: 'It runs every time a new LSA is received:',
        answer: 3,
        },							
        {
        question:
        "14. Which of the following correctly identifies the order of steps for two OSPF routers to become fully adjacent?",
        choice1: 'Exchange, Loading, SPF, Adjacent',
        choice2: 'Exchange, ExStart, Loading',
        choice3: 'ExStart, Exchange, Loading, Full',
        choice4: 'ExStart, Exchange, Loading, Adjacent',
        answer: 3,
        },							
        {
        question:
        "15. Which of the following default metrics is not correct for the given interface speed?",
        choice1: '1 Gbps link = 100',
        choice2: '16 Mbps link = 6,250',
        choice3: '1.544 Mbps link = 64,766',
        choice4: '622 Mbps link = 16',
        answer: 4,
    
    
	
        }
    
]

const SCORE_POINTS = 1
const MAX_QUESTIONS = 20

startGame = () => {
    questionCounter = 0
    score = 0
    availableQuestions = [...questions]
    getNewQuestion()
}

getNewQuestion = () => {
    if(availableQuestions.length === 0 || questionCounter > MAX_QUESTIONS) {
        localStorage.setItem('mostRecentScore', score)

        return window.location.assign('/end.html')
    }

    questionCounter++
    progressText.innerText = `Question ${questionCounter} of ${MAX_QUESTIONS}`
    progressBarFull.style.width = `${(questionCounter/MAX_QUESTIONS) * 100}%`
    
    const questionsIndex = Math.floor(Math.random() * availableQuestions.length)
    currentQuestion = availableQuestions[questionsIndex]
    question.innerText = currentQuestion.question

    choices.forEach(choice => {
        const number = choice.dataset['number']
        choice.innerText = currentQuestion['choice' + number]
    })

    availableQuestions.splice(questionsIndex, 1)

    acceptingAnswers = true
}

choices.forEach(choice => {
    choice.addEventListener('click', e => {
        if(!acceptingAnswers) return

        acceptingAnswers = false
        const selectedChoice = e.target
        const selectedAnswer = selectedChoice.dataset['number']

        let classToApply = selectedAnswer == currentQuestion.answer ? 'correct' : 'incorrect'

        if(classToApply === 'correct') {
            incrementScore(SCORE_POINTS)
        }

        selectedChoice.parentElement.classList.add(classToApply)

        setTimeout(() => {
            selectedChoice.parentElement.classList.remove(classToApply)
            getNewQuestion()

        }, 1000)
    })
})

incrementScore = num => {
    score +=num
    scoreText.innerText = score
}

startGame()